Guide to the International Order of Oddfellows, Braddock's Field Lodge #529, Braddock, Pa. Records, 1857-1975 AIS.1982.25
ULS Archives & Special Collections
International Order of Oddfellows, Braddock's Field Lodge #529, Braddock, Pa. Records
1857-1975
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Independent Order of Odd Fellows. Braddock's Field Lodge No. 529 (Braddock, Pa.)
AIS.1982.25
6 microfilm_reels
These records span the years 1857-1975 but are concentrated mostly in the period 1900-1975. The records contain minutes; membership rolls and application books; financial records; forms; and a small amount of correspondence.
History
Founded on March 31, 1857, the Braddock's Field Lodge #529, Independent Order of Odd Fellows functioned as a social and beneficial order until its merger with the Wilmerding Lodge #1076 in April 1976. A secret fraternal organization, the Oddfellows were dedicated to aiding members in times of illness or distress, conducting funerals for deceased members, and providing aid for member's widows and orphans. The lodge also served as a social club, drawing members from all walks of life.
Scope and Content Notes
These records span the years 1857-1975 but are concentrated mostly in the period 1900-1975. The records contain minutes (including one minute book from the McMasters Encampment of the Patriarchs Militant, an adjunct of Oddfellows); membership rolls and application books; financial records; forms; and a small amount of correspondence.
Series III includes Membership Proposition Books that give name, date, residence, age, occupation, and reference; Membership Application Books that give name, date, occupation, age, residence, health, and oath; and Miscellaneous Membership Items that include Transfer Certificate, Reinstatement Certificates, list of members on relief (no date), and list of 50 year members, 1955. Series IV includes Cash Records, Receipt Books (that give date, name, amount, and disbursing officer), and Dues Ledger Book. Series V includes Meritorious Service Awards, 1941; Manual of Instructions, 1956; Funeral Ceremony, IOOF, no date; and Rules and Regulations for Public Installations, no date.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These records were microfilmed by the Archives of Industrial Society, 1982.
Previous Citation
International Order of Oddfellows, Braddock's Field Lodge #529, Braddock, Pa., Records, AIS.1982.25, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Societies; Braddock (Pa.) -- Social life and customs; Independent Order of Odd Fellows. Braddock's Field Lodge No. 529 (Braddock, Pa.)
- Constitution and By-laws, 1931-1947; I.
  - Rules of the Order, 1931 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 1, Item 1)
  - Rules of the Order, 1947 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 1, Item 2)
- Minutes, 1857-1975; II.
  - Minutes, March 31, 1857 - November 19, 1864 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 1, Item 3)
  - Minutes, July 6, 1894 - December 27, 1901 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 1, Item 4)
  - Minutes, April 6, 1917 - February 26, 1926 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 1, Item 5)
  - Minutes, March 6, 1931 - August 23, 1935 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 1, Item 6)
  - Minutes, August 30, 1935 - June 23, 1939 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 2, Item 1)
  - Minutes, June 30, 1939 - August 20, 1943 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 2, Item 2)
  - Minutes, April 30, 1948 - September 25, 1953 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 2, Item 3)
  - Minutes, October 2, 1953 - December 12, 1958 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 2, Item 4)
  - Minutes, December 19, 1958 - December 29, 1961 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 2, Item 5)
  - Minutes, January 5, 1962 - December 27, 1968 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 3, Item 1)
  - Minutes, January 3, 1969 - December 29, 1972 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 3, Item 2)
  - Minutes, January 5, 1973 - September 26, 1975 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 3, Item 3)
  - Minutes, McMasters Encampment, 1913-1945 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 4, Item 1)
- Membership Records, 1881-1968; III.
  - Membership Proposition Books, March 27, 1891 - May 19, 1905 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 4, Item 2)
  - Membership Records, June 9, 1905 - November 3, 1916 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 4, Item 3)
  - Membership Records, October 27, 1916 - March 4, 1938 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 4, Item 4)
  - Roll of Members Book, February 10, 1896 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 4, Item 5)
  - Rules of Order and Initiation Record Book, May 8, 1896 - January 3, 1913 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 4, Item 6)
  - Roll of Officers Book, April 11, 1919 - October 10, 1941 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 4, Item 7)
  - Membership Application Book, February 18, 1881 - July 8, 1904 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 4, Item 8)
  - Membership Application Book, September 2, 1904 - January 5, 1917 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 4, Item 9)
  - Membership Application Book, February 2, 1917 - March 6, 1942 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 5, Item 1)
  - Membership Application Book, April 3, 1942 - October 18, 1968 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 5, Item 2)
  - Miscellaneous Membership Items, 1897-1955 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 5, Item 3)
- Financial Records, IV.
  - Cash Record Books, 1.
    - Cash Record Books, October 3, 1890 - March 25, 1898 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 5, Item 4)
    - Cash Record Books, April 1, 1898 - December 27, 1901 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 5, Item 5)
    - Cash Record Books, January 3, 1902 - June 29, 1906 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 5, Item 6)
    - Cash Record Books, July 6, 1906 - September 29, 1911 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 5, Item 7)
    - Cash Record Books, October 6, 1911 - September 27, 1918 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 5, Item 8)
    - Cash Record Books, October 11, 1918 - June 27, 1924 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 5, Item 9)
    - Cash Record Books, October 5, 1934 - September 28, 1945 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 6, Item 1)
    - Cash Record Books, October 5, 1945 - May 18, 1956 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 6, Item 2)
    - Cash Record Books, May 25, 1956 - March 26, 1971 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 6, Item 3)
  - Receipt Books, 2.
    - Receipt Book, March 31, 1857 - July 13, 1865 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 6, Item 4)
  - Receipt Book, July 27, 1865 - September 30, 1873 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 6, Item 5)
  - Dues Ledger Books, 3.
    - Dues Ledger Books, November 1870 - March 1881 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 6, Item 6)
    - Dues Ledger Books, April 1909 - October 1915 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 6, Item 7)
    - Dues Ledger Books, December 1924 - July 1931 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 6, Item 8)
- Regulations, V.
  - Volume 1, 1941-1956 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 6, Item 9)
- Correspondence, VI.
  - Volume 1, 1932-1956 (Microfilm-cabinet 2, Reel 6, Item 10)